English, Department of; Records ua603
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Department of English Records
1939-2000
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ua603
9.33 cubic ft.
Contains inactive records of the Department of English, including syllabi and course materials, annual reports, departmental correspondence, department publications, and administrative records.
Collection X
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Historical Note
English language and literature instruction at the University dates back to the founding of the New York State Normal School in 1844. The M.A. in English was first offered in 1962, and a Ph.D. was offered the following year. A Doctor of Arts in English was introduced in 1971, intended for students preparing for a career in teaching, rather than research. The D.A. program was discontinued in 1995. Currently, the Department of English offers a B.A., an Honors B.A., a combined B.A./M.A., several minors, and graduate work leading to an M.A. or Ph.D.
Scope and Contents
This collection Administrative files series includes a number of files documenting the day-to-day functions of the Department of English, including departmental memoranda, class enrollment profiles, space planning documentation, meeting minutes, and correspondence. This collection also contains a number of documents related to curriculum development, including course syllabi and proposed revisions to major requirements. The Publications series of this collection contains informational pamphlets for prospective students prepared by the Department as well as literary magazines administered by the Department containing by student and non-student writers. Finally, the Schweitzer Chair Records contain grant applications, promotional materials, fellowship applications and correspondence regarding Chair initiatives around the time period in which Toni Morrison served as the Chair (1985-1989). The bulk of the collection dates from 1970-1990.
Arrangement of the Collection
Files in administrative series were maintained in their original order upon processing. The publication series has been organized by publication and arranged chronologically. The Schweitzer Chair records have been maintained in their original order upon processing.
Literature; Education, Higher--Administration; English language; curricula; Syllabi; Annual reports; UAlbany Academic Departments; State University of New York at Albany
- Administrative Files, 1939-1990; Undated; 6 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series is made up of administrative documents concerning the day-to-day functions of the Department of English, including departmental memoranda, class enrollment profiles, five-year plans, budgetary printouts, meeting minutes, and correspondence. This series contains a number of files related to curriculum development, including course syllabi, proposals for new classes and class descriptions, as well as revisions to the undergraduate English major, the Doctorate of Arts and the Ph.D. program. This series also includes a number of files documenting winners of the Leah Lovenheim awards, given yearly for the best piece of fiction or poetry by a University at Albany undergraduate. Some of the Lovenheim records date back to 1943. This series also contains materials related to institutes and programs administered by the department, such as the New York Writers' Institute.
  Additionally, this series contains some materials related to Shields McIlwaine, a department chairman whose tenure at the University dates back to the 1939. The McIlwaine materials mostly consist of obituary writeups, several letters of recommendation given to him at the University of Chicago and transcripts of several lectures he delivered during his time in Albany.
  Arrangement
  Files in this series were maintained in their original order upon processing.
  - Budget, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CDHP, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Computer Services, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Council, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dean, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Film Services, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Five Year Plan, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Faculty, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Programs, 1984
  - Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Institute for International Writers & Artists, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interdisciplinary Programs, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Linguistics, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Research Committee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Academic Affairs, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Admissions, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Affirmative Action, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Commencement, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Evaluation Policy, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Committee on Nominations and Elections, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Community Relations, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Computer Services, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Continuing Education, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Council on Educational Policy, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Employee Assistance Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Finance and Business, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General Education Requirements, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Graduate Academic Council, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Review of Doctoral Programs, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Institutional Research, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - International Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Library, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Personnel Policies, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - President, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Printing, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Programs and Priorities, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Registrar, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Department Directors & Curriculum, Fall 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Spring, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Enrollment Stats, Fall 1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fall, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Key Memos, Fall 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Spring, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Department Directories, Spring 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Key Memos, Spring 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Enrollment Stats, Fall 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Garber Full Time Enrollment Statistics, Fall 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Writing Contest, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Advisory Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Key Memos, Fall 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Department Directories, Spring 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Memoranda, Spring 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Key Memos, Spring 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Enrollment Stats, Fall 1983 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Department Directories, Fall 1983 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Memoranda, Fall 1983 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Writing Contest, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Course Offering, Summer 1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Registration Summaries, Spring 1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1983 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Spring 1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Schedule, Fall 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Enrollment Stats, Fall 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Fall 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Department Directories, Fall 1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Summer 1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Writing Contest, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Section Verification Lists, Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Directories, Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1982 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Enrollment Study, Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lapinski Statistics, Fall 1981-Spring 1985 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Directories, Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Memoranda, Fall 1981 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Writing Contest, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, Summer 1981 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1981 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1981 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Spring 1981 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Department Directories, Spring 1981 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1980 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Enrollment Stats, Fall 1980 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Grad Section Verification Lists, Fall 1980 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Department Directories, Fall 1980 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Writing Contest, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Final Grade Reporting, Spring 1980 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1980 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Faculty Roster, Spring 1980 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Directories, Spring 1980 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1980 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Section Verification Lists, Fall 1979 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Enrollment Stats, Fall 1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Departmental Directories, Fall 1979 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Term Renewals, Spring 1988 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Personnel Summaries, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Personnel Summaries, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Personnel Summaries, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Personnel Summaries, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Poise Forms, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Carol Berge, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Metcalf - March 1984 Writer-in-Residence (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Brom Weber, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Senate, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student Affairs, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Talented Students Admission Program, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Undergraduate Education, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - UUP, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - SUNY Winter's Festival, April 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Arts Program, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Conversations in the Discipline, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Council on Writing, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - English Programs, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Research Foundation, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - University Awards Programs, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - AWP, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Capital Region Center, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - CCCC, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - CDWP, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - English Department, 1975-1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hudson-Mohawk Association, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mid-Hudson MLA, 1983 May (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - MLA, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - ADE, 1976-1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - ADE, Summer 1986 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - English Institute, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - NEH, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - NEMLA Panel, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NEMLA, 1978-1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - NYCEA, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - NYCH, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - NYFS Albany Meeting, September 10-11, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - NYSEC, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - SED, 1978-1983 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - SED Reports on Doctorate of Arts, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Doctorate of Arts - SED Documents, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - GAC/SED General, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Doctorate of Arts - Albany Documents, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Self-Study Report, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - D.A. Self-Study Report, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Proposed Ph.D. in Rhetoric and Communication, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ph.D. Letter of Intent, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ph.D. Current File, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rhetoric Department, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ph.D. in Humanties, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Ph.D. in French, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - French Ph.D. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Ph.D. Background, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Holman Report, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ph.D. - Report of HolmanNendler/Wood, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ph.D. - Other Programs, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ph.D. - Reports of Advisory Committee, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ph.D. - Litigation, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Ph.D. Self Study, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ph.D. 1971 Report (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - University Faculty, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Part-Time Applications, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Part-Time Applications, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Tenure and Promotion Memoranda, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Writing Advisiory, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Review of SUNY Albany Baccalaureate Programs, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Undergraduate Program, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Undergraduate Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Undergraduate Education, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - WMHT Project, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Research and Professional, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Ph.D. in Doscourse Theory, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - QBK, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Research Foundation, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Salaries, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - S.E.D. Review Committee, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - SUNYA, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Teaching, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Departmental Three Year Plan, 1976-1979 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Humanities College Three-Year Plan, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Three Year Plan University, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Travel Guidelines, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Travel, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Recruiting, 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Graduate Advisory, 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Graduate Program, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Graduate Study - SUNYA, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - G.R.E., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Graduate Programs - Public Relations, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Departmental Reports, Spring 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Statistics, Fall 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Statistics, Spring 1974 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, Spring 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Statistics, Fall 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report, Spring 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Statistics, Spring 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Statistics, Fall 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Enrollment Stats, Spring 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Statistics, Spring 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brochures, Spring 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Memos, Spring 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Information for Grad Students, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Master of Arts Program, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Leaves, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Student Enrollment Information, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Employment Applications, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Part-Time Staff, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Part-time Appointments, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Mini-course Appointments, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Fellowships/Assistantships, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Advisory Committee, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Budget, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Budget, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Leaves, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Discretionary Salary Increases, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Enrollment Analysis, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Task Force on Priorities, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Slush Fund, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Brochure, Fall 1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Staff Notes and Course Catalog, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Notes, Spring 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - English Department Draft Brochure, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, Spring 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Administrative Memos, Spring 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Directories, Spring 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1978 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Memos, Fall 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Department Brochures, Fall 1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Staffing Requests, Fall 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Undergraduate Academic Council, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - By-Laws, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Administrative Memos, Fall 1977 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Brochure, Fall 1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Summer 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Statistics, Fall 1976 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Annual Report, Spring 1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Three Year Plans, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Three Year Plans, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1979 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1980 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1980 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1981 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1984 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1985 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, Fall 1985 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Schedule Information and Sabbaticals, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Graduate Program, Spring 1984 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Graduate Program, Fall 1984 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Graduate Program, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Graduate Advisory Committee, Fall 1987 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Graduate Advisory Committee, Spring 1988 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Administrative Memos, Fall 1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Administrative Memos, Fall 1981 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Administrative Memos, Spring 1982 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Administrative Memos, Fall 1982 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Administrative Memos, Spring 1983 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - ADAPT, Fall 1986 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Graduate Program, Fall 1983 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Graduate Program, Spring 1983 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Graduate Program, Fall 1981 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Graduate Program, Spring 1982 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Lana Cable Review, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Budget 1993-94 Part Time, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Budget, Fall 1993-Spring 1994 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Budget Information, Fall 1994-Spring 1995 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Part-time Lines and TA Assignments, Fall 1994 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Retirements, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Rowley Retirement, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Student Conduct Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Budget Allocations, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Tenure and Promotion Guidelines, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Tenure and Promotion Guidelines, Spring 1977 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Secretarial Reclassification, Fall 1989 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Department Profiles, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Released Time, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Newsletters, 1977-1989 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Advisement Survey, Fall 1992 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Budget Allocation, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Budget Figures, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Sabbaticals, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Conference Funding Application, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - XEROX Machine Billing and Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - VP Special Course Initiatives, Summer 1995 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, Spring 1993 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Lovenheim Awards, Spring 1943 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Lovenheim Awards, Spring 1944 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Lovenheim Awards, Spring 1945 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Lovenheim Awards, Spring 1946 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Lovenheim Awards, Spring 1947 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Lovenheim Awards, Spring 1949 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Departmental Reports, Spring 1964 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Grade Inflation Reviews, 1968-1975 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Departmental Files, Fall 1994 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Cultures of Conflict and Reconciliation English Lecture Series, Undated (Box 6, Folder 83)
- Schweitzer Chair Records, 1985-1989; 1 cubic ft.
  This series contains the records of Suzanne Lance, Fellowship Coordinator and Special Projects Officer for the Schweitzer Chair. The series documents Toni Morrison's tenure as the Schweitzer Chair. Contains grant applications, promotional materials, and correspondence regarding Schweitzer Chair initiatives. Also includes correspondence and copies of published writing from Schweitzer Fellows. Morrison's correspondence within the collection primarily concerns Schweitzer Chair initiatives. Additionally, this series contains flat files of posters and fliers for events sponsored by the Schweitzer Chair.
- Publications, 1945-2000; 2.33 cubic ft.
  This series is made up of publications produced by the English Department for students and the public at large. This includes "News About English," a pamphlet containing departmental course listings and advising information (1977-2000) as well as various student literary magazines administered by the English Department at different times, Including Primer and Tangent. Additionally, this series contains a number of external publications produced by people and groups connected to the Department of English. This includes The Little Magazine, a literary magazine produced by the Writing Program at SUNY Albany (1966-1994) and 13th Moon, a feminist literary magazine edited by Judith E. Johnson, a professor of Writing and Women's Studies at the University at Albany, SUNY.
  Materials in this series are arranged chronologically by by publication.